<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grünwald lab</title>
    <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grünwald lab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plantopia podcast interview with Matt Kasson</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/plantopia-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/plantopia-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About this Episode&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined host Matt Kasson for an engaging conversation about emerging Phytophthora diseases, the importance of interdisciplinary research and collaboration in addressing global agricultural challenges, and exciting developments in plant health research, including gene editing, high-throughput data analysis, and robotic phenotyping.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome, Logan!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/logan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/logan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We warmly welcome USDA ARS postdoc Logan Blair to the Grunwald lab. He will join the team to further develop the &lt;code&gt;nf-core\pathogensurveillance&lt;/code&gt; computational pipeline to diagnose pathogens using whole genome sequences. He will also conduct population genomic research on &lt;strong&gt;Phytophthora&lt;/strong&gt; pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Cauldron</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/carlesonphd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/carlesonphd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dr. Nick Cauldron for graduating with a PhD in Plant Pathology. Nick conducted comparative genomic research on the sudden oak death pathogen. We will miss your expertise and wit in the lab very much. We wish you the best of luck in your next adventure in the lab of Christina Cuomo at Brown University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome, Camilo!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/camilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/camilo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We warmly welcome postdoc Camilo Parada-Rojas to the Grunwald and Chang labs. He will use a range of comparative and population genomic tools to understand Phytophthora emergence. Currently, he is busy sequencing genomes using Oxford nanopore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camilo graduated with a PhD from @QuesadaLabNCSU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Martha!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/sudermann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/sudermann/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Martha Sudermann for obtaining a competitive USDA NIFA postdoctoral fellowship. The overarching goal of this work is to understand pathogen emergence and processes that facilitate adaptation and host shift to western hemlock. She will focus on Phytophthora pluvialis, which is a pathogen on conifer species that are native to the PNW and threaten mixed-conifer wildland forests and plantations. Phytophthora pluvialis is a recalcitrant organism, and genomic approaches to characterize its populations will allow us to describe the genetic basis of adaptation of the pathogen to novel hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Nick Carleson!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/carleson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/carleson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Nick Carelson for obtaining a competitive USDA NIFA predoctoral fellowship. The grant aims to cultivate future academic, industry, or government leaders who can solve emerging agricultural challenges of the 21st century. Nick&amp;rsquo;s award will support his research on evolutionary genomics of the sudden oak death pathogen, Phytophthora ramorum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcoming Martha, Fernanda, Ricardo and Zach!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/new-postdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/new-postdocs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We warmly welcome a cluster hire of four postdocs to collaborate on developing novel approaches for tracing pathogens and microbiomes using whole genome sequences, transcriptomics and population/comparative genomics. This is a joint effort with Jared LeBoldus and Jeff Chang at Oregon State University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSU BPP Spring Seminar 2021 videos</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/bpp_seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/bpp_seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://media.oregonstate.edu/channel/Department%2Bof%2BBotany%2Band%2BPlant%2BPathology%2BSeminars/209417243&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Video links&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bpp.oregonstate.edu/bpp/about/seminars&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2021 OSU Spring Seminar video series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcoming Andrew Tupper to the lab!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/tupper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/tupper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We welcome Dr. Andrew Tupper to our group. Andrew graduated with a PhD degree in Biochemistry and Astrobiology from McMaster University in Hamilton, ON, Canada. He previously received his BS in Interdisciplinary Studies from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in Troy, NY. Andrew has published research with intriguing titles such as &amp;lsquo;Can the RNA World Still Function without
Cytidine?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew joins our group to conduct comparative genomic analyses of &lt;em&gt;Phytophthora ramorum&lt;/em&gt; and close relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Foster!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/foster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/foster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;👏 Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=A_KrMroAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zach Foster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who graduated with a Ph.D. in Molecular and Cellular Biology 🚀 from Oregon State University. Zach has been very productive producing two R packages, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005404&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;metacoder&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.14013.2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;taxa&lt;/a&gt; as well as publishing several papers before his defense. We could not be prouder of you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here he is at the recent &lt;strong&gt;Plant Health&lt;/strong&gt; meeting in Tampa, FL presenting his innovative visualization for microbiome data we call heat trees and implemented in the &lt;code&gt;metacoder&lt;/code&gt; R package:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/img/Foster_APS_Meeting_Metacoder.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Zach presenting his work on the metacoder package and heattrees in Tampa, FL, 2016 at the APS meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zach has given numerous presentations nationally and internationally on analyzing microbiome data in R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Shakya!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/shakya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/shakya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;👏 Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bpp.oregonstate.edu/users/shankar-shakya&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shankar Shakya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who graduated with a Ph.D. in Plant Pathology 🚀 from Oregon State University. Shankar, who got his undergraduate degree from Nepal, had to overcome many obstacles to make it to this point. Congrats to Shankar for doing a phenomenal job with a great seminar and a rigorous thesis defense. We could not be prouder of you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here he is at the recent &lt;strong&gt;Plant Health 2019&lt;/strong&gt; meeting in Cleveland, OH with his colleagues from the University of Florida where he got his MSc in Plant Pathology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/img/UFlorida.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shankar with his peers from UF at Plant Health 2019&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Phytophthora Preparedness Workshop, Melbourne, Australia</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was honored to be invited to present our research on translational applications of genomics to manage &lt;em&gt;Phytophthora&lt;/em&gt; pathogens at the workshop convened in Melbourne, Australia by Biosecurity Queensland of the Department of Agriculture and Fisheries. The workshop provided me with a deep appreciation for all the excellent work being done in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Plant Pathology (OPP) interview</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/opp_interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/opp_interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Plant Pathology &lt;a href=&#34;https://openplantpathology.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPP&lt;/a&gt; provides a series of interviews with scientists in &lt;strong&gt;Plant Pathology&lt;/strong&gt; or related areas who have embraced open science and contributed knowledge and tools to advance the field. OPP is a community of plant pathologists, mostly computationally-oriented, that supports  several forms of Open Science practices. We support efforts from individuals or groups to develop and deliver next-generation databases and tools for plant pathology-related subjects and applications using open source software, data and repositories. Check out the interview:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIP Workshop in Lima, Peru</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/cip-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/cip-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to be invited to a workshop that also featured my dear colleague Jim Bradeen. We both gave a seminar on our work. I then gave a hands-on workshop on conducting population genomic data analysis in R. It was fun working with a very active group of colleagues from South America. I thank Willmer Perez and Jorge Andrade for inviting me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun seeing the wonderful and tasty phenotypic diversity of potatoes CIP catalogs:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metacoder heat-tree wins PLoS t-shirt competition</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/t-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/t-shirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zach Foster won the t-shirt design &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.plos.org/biologue/2018/06/29/plos-computational-biology-t-shirt-design-winner-announced-2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt; conducted over twitter by PLoS Computational Biology with his differential heat-tree design. Heat-trees show differential abundance of OTUs across two pairwise comparisons in a hierarchical, tree-based format. The heat-tree concept was first introduced in our paper on the R package &lt;em&gt;metacoder&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005404&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; and the winning design for the t-shirt is inspired by figure 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This t-shirt was given away at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iscb.org/ismb2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ISMB 2018&lt;/a&gt; conference in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now all proudly wearing his design:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Fry retires</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/fry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pppmb.cals.cornell.edu/people/william-fry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bill Fry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, my postdoctoral mentor, finally retired from Cornell&amp;rsquo;s SIPS. He hosted all his lab members for a memorable party. I learned a lot from Bill in terms of conducting research, project management, networking, service to our institutions and field, and how to conduct research. Thanks Bill, for your kind and deep mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Dr. Tabima!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/tabima/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/tabima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;👏 Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.oregonstate.edu/~tabimaj/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Tabima&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who graduated with a stellar record with a Ph.D. in Plant Pathology from Oregon State University. Besides getting many travel awards, Javier has also been awarded several prestigious awards including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CAS Savery Outstanding Doctoral Student Award. 2017. College of Agricultural
Sciences, Oregon State University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenore Bayley Fellow (2016-2017). Oregon State University. &lt;a href=&#34;http://gradschool.oregonstate.edu/awards/recipients/javier-tabima&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link at OSU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invited Oral Presentation “Searching for genomic signatures of host jumping onto
raspberry and strawberry in two Phytophthora sister taxa”. American&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invited special session talk: “Plant Pathologist of the Future”, American Phytopathological Society meeting. 2016. Representing APS Pacific Division.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Zach Foster!</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/ropensci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/ropensci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;👏 Congratulations to Zach Foster for successfully comepting to obtain an ROpenSci scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ariena van Bruggen retires from the University of Florida</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/van-bruggen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/post/van-bruggen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epi.ufl.edu/people/faculty-profiles/ariena-h-c-van-bruggen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariena H. C. van Bruggen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, my PhD mentor, retires from the University of Florida. I was lucky to be able to participate in her memorable retirement symposium entitled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epi.ufl.edu/people/faculty-profiles/ariena-h-c-van-bruggen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microbial Cycling in Food Webs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The symposium was a resounding success and we all wish Ariena the best in retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grunwald.github.io/grunwaldlab/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/blogdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blogdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package. The theme was forked from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme&lt;/a&gt; and modified by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yihui/hugo-lithium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yihui Xie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
